NGINX JS DOM — Full-Proxy Programming Guide

Introduction

What JS-Pilgrim Provides

The NGINX JS DOM exposes the nginx configuration tree as a JavaScript object model (COM) and lets JavaScript handle HTTP requests. JS-Pilgrim is the layer above the COM: it gives JavaScript complete control over every phase of connection and request processing.

Without JS-Pilgrim, JavaScript can read and mutate configuration, assign request handlers to locations, and install body filters (see the Filters Guide [js-filters-guide.adoc]). With JS-Pilgrim, JavaScript also controls:

•

Accept hooks — fire immediately after accept(2), before HTTP parsing. Inspect or reject connections by IP address, rate limit at TCP level.

•

L4 stream filters — transform raw byte streams in both directions before or after HTTP processing, without writing a C module.

•

Request phase hooks — run before the content handler at location, server, or global HTTP scope. Async hooks, middleware-style next() wrapping, and early req.respond() short-circuit are all supported.

•

Response hooks — modify response headers after the content handler has selected them, before they are sent to the client.

•

Upstream filters — transform the body sent to or received from a proxied backend, in addition to the client-side body filters.

•

Per-request context — a plain JS object (req.ctx) that persists across async suspend/resume and across the access-phase → content-phase boundary.

•

Cross-worker shared state — nginx.shared, a flat key/value store backed by shared memory, visible to all worker processes simultaneously.

•

Master lifecycle events — nginx.on('workerSpawned', fn) and friends let JS react to nginx process events.

•

Module packaging — nginx.use(path, config) loads directory-based plugin packages; nginx.install(fn, config) installs inline plugins.

The Layered Architecture

Every incoming connection passes through a stack of independently programmable layers:

Client TCP
↓
[Accept hooks] listener.on / server.on (sync)
↓
[L4 inbound filters] listener/server.addL4Filter (async gen*)
↓
[HTTP parsing] nginx built-in
↓
[Access phase hooks] nginx.http.addHook / server.addHook (async, next())
↓
[Content phase hooks] location.addHook (async, next())
↓
[Content handler] location.handler or nginx built-in
↓
[Header filter] location.addResponseHook (sync)
↓
[Body filter] location.addBodyFilter (see Filters Guide)
↓
[Upstream req filter] location.addUpstreamRequestFilter (async gen*)
↓
[Upstream response filter] location.addUpstreamFilter (async gen*)
↓
[L4 outbound filters] listener/server.addL4SendFilter (async gen*)
↓
Client TCP

A layer that does nothing passes through automatically. A layer that calls req.respond() (or conn.reject()) short-circuits everything below it.

How to Read This Guide

This guide covers JS-Pilgrim hooks and filters. For the COM object tree (nginx.http.servers[], upstream config, SSL settings, etc.) see the Developer Manual [js-dom-manual.adoc]. For body filters (addBodyFilter, addHeaderFilter) see the Filters Guide [js-filters-guide.adoc]. For dynamic reconfiguration (write_mode, snapshot(), restore()) see the Reconfiguration Guide [js-reconfig-guide.adoc].

All JS-Pilgrim hooks must be registered from a js_source script that runs at config time (before workers are forked), unless stated otherwise.

Request Phase Hooks

Overview

Request phase hooks are JS callbacks that run inside nginx’s access or content phase, before the content handler produces a response. They share a three- outcome model:

Outcome │ Behaviour

Return normally (no req.respond()) │ Hook passes — the chain advances to the next hook or to the content handler.

req.respond(status, headers, body) │ Chain stops — remaining hooks and the content handler are skipped.

throw / rejected Promise │ nginx logs the error and sends a 500 response.

Location Hooks:location.addHook(fn)

Location hooks fire in the content phase for every request matched to that location.

const loc = nginx.http.servers[0].locations[0];
// Synchronous hook
loc.addHook(function(req) {
if (!req.headers['x-api-key']) {
req.respond(401, {}, 'Missing API key\n');
}
});
// Asynchronous hook
loc.addHook(async function(req) {
const result = await nginx.setTimeout(10); // yield to event loop
req.respond(200, {}, 'ok\n');
});

Returns location for chaining. Multiple addHook calls register multiple hooks; they run in registration order.

Server Hooks:server.addHook(fn)

Server hooks fire in the access phase for every request that matches the virtual server, regardless of which location ultimately handles the request.

nginx.http.servers[0].addHook(async function(req) {
if (req.uri.startsWith('/internal/')) {
req.respond(403, {}, 'Forbidden\n');
}
});

Global HTTP Hooks:nginx.http.addHook(fn)

Global HTTP hooks fire in the access phase for every request handled by the HTTP block, across all virtual servers.

nginx.http.addHook(function(req) {
nginx.log(nginx.INFO,
'[global] ' + req.method + ' ' + req.uri);
});

Execution Order

For a given request, hooks execute in the order: global HTTP hooks → server hooks → content-phase (location) hooks → content handler.

Within each scope, hooks run in the order they were registered.

Async Hooks

Any hook callback may be an async function. When a hook returns a pending Promise, nginx suspends the request (incrementing r→main→count) and returns NGX_DONE. The event loop continues processing other connections. When the Promise settles, ngx_js_async_check resumes the request.

nginx.http.addHook(async function(req) {
// Simulate an async token validation call
await nginx.setTimeout(20);
var token = req.headers['authorization'] || '';
if (!token.startsWith('Bearer ')) {
req.respond(401, {}, 'Unauthorized\n');
}
// otherwise: pass through to next hook / content handler
});

Only one request is suspended per worker at a time (serialised through the event loop). For high-concurrency async gating, use a SharedWorker.

Middleware Chains:next()

Every hook callback receives an optional second argument next. Calling next() runs the remaining hooks in the chain and returns a Promise that resolves when they complete. Code after await next() runs before the content handler.

// Wrap an entire hook chain with timing
loc.addHook(async function(req, next) {
var t0 = Date.now();
await next(); // run remaining hooks
var elapsed = Date.now() - t0;
nginx.log(nginx.INFO, 'hook chain took ' + elapsed + 'ms');
// content handler runs after this function returns
});
loc.addHook(function(req) {
req.respond(200, {}, 'hello\n');
});

Hooks that do not call next() auto-advance (backward-compatible with pre-P9 code). Calling next() more than once returns the cached result.

The chain runner is a Koa-style middleware stack:

hook A (calls next())
hook B (calls next())
[no more hooks → next() resolves immediately]
hook B post-next code
hook A post-next code
[chain settles → content handler runs]

Per-Request Context:req.ctx

req.ctx is a plain JS object allocated on first access and tied to the nginx request pool. It persists across async suspend/resume and across the access-phase → content-phase boundary, making it the right place to pass data from an access hook to the content handler.

// Access-phase hook: validate and store decoded token
nginx.http.addHook(async function(req) {
var token = parseJWT(req.headers['authorization']);
if (!token) {
req.respond(401, {}, 'Unauthorized\n');
return;
}
req.ctx.user = token.sub; // survives async suspend
req.ctx.role = token.role;
});
// Content handler: read token data stored by the hook
loc.handler = function(req) {
req.respond(200, {}, 'Hello, ' + req.ctx.user + '\n');
};

req.ctx is lazily created on first access. It is freed automatically via ngx_pool_cleanup_add when the request ends. It is undefined before first access (reading it does not allocate).

Response Hooks

3.1.location.addResponseHook(fn)

Response hooks fire after the content handler has set response headers, before they are sent to the client.

loc.addResponseHook(function(req) {
// Inspect and mutate response headers
req.setResponseHeader('x-powered-by', 'nginx-js');
req.removeResponseHeader('server');
// Read or change the status code
if (req.status === 404) {
req.status = 200;
// body is already determined at this point
}
});

Returns location for chaining. Multiple calls register multiple response hooks; they run in registration order.

Upstream Filters

Upstream filters run in the body-filter chain but only when the location proxies to an upstream (proxy_pass, fastcgi_pass, etc.). They are independent of addBodyFilter.

Response Body:location.addUpstreamFilter(fn)

Transforms the upstream’s response body before it reaches the client.

loc.addUpstreamFilter(async function*(body, req) {
// body — full upstream response body as a string
yield body.replace(/internal-hostname/g, 'public-hostname');
});
// Chain two upstream response filters
loc.addUpstreamFilter(async function*(body, req) {
yield body.toUpperCase();
});
loc.addUpstreamFilter(async function*(body, req) {
yield '[' + body + ']'; // receives output of first filter
});

Request Body:location.addUpstreamRequestFilter(fn)

Transforms the client’s request body before it is forwarded to the upstream.

loc.addUpstreamRequestFilter(async function*(body, req) {
// body — full client request body as a string
var obj = JSON.parse(body);
obj.processed_by = 'nginx-js';
yield JSON.stringify(obj);
});

Chaining

Multiple addUpstreamFilter calls chain in registration order: the output of filter N becomes the input of filter N+1. The same applies to addUpstreamRequestFilter.

Accept Hooks

Accept hooks fire immediately after accept(2), before nginx begins HTTP parsing. They can inspect or reject connections based on TCP-level information.

On JS-Managed Listeners:listener.on('accept', fn)

For listeners created with nginx.http.attach(sock):

const sock = nginx.createSocket('0.0.0.0:8443');
const lst = nginx.http.attach(sock);
lst.addServer(defaultSrv);
lst.on('accept', function(conn) {
if (!isAllowed(conn.remoteAddr)) {
conn.reject();
}
});

On Standard Listen Sockets:server.on('accept', fn)

For sockets declared with nginx’s listen directive:

// server {} whose listen directive owns port 8080
var srv = nginx.http.servers.find(function(s) {
return s.name === 'my-server';
});
srv.on('accept', function(conn) {
nginx.log(nginx.INFO,
'new connection from ' + conn.remoteAddr);
});

server.on() installs the hook during init_conf by replacing ls→handler on every listen socket whose default server is srv.

NginxConnection

Both APIs deliver a NginxConnection object to the callback:

Property / Method │ Type │ Description

conn.remoteAddr │ string (read-only) │ Client IP address, e.g. "192.168.1.10". IPv4 and IPv6.

conn.remotePort │ number (read-only) │ Client TCP port, e.g. 54321.

conn.reject() │ void │ Close the connection immediately. All remaining accept hooks are skipped; nginx never starts HTTP processing for this connection.

Constraints

Accept hooks are synchronous only. Returning a pending Promise from an accept hook causes the connection to be rejected and a warning to be logged.

Multiple on('accept', fn) calls register multiple hooks; they run in registration order. If any hook calls conn.reject(), subsequent hooks are not called.

L4 Stream Filters

L4 filters intercept raw byte streams at the TCP level, before or after HTTP processing. They are expressed as async generator functions — the JS-Pilgrim stream primitive.

Inbound:addL4Filter(fn)

Intercepts bytes travelling from client to nginx, before the HTTP parser sees them.

6.1.1. On JS-managed listeners

listener.addL4Filter(async function*(source) {
for await (const chunk of source) {
// chunk — Uint8Array of raw TCP bytes
yield chunk; // pass through unchanged
return;
}
});

6.1.2. On standard listen sockets

srv.addL4Filter(async function*(source) {
for await (const chunk of source) {
const s = String.fromCharCode(...chunk);
yield s.startsWith('MAGIC:') ? s.slice(6) : s;
return;
}
});

6.1.3. Generator protocol

The source argument is a async iterable [https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Iteration_protocols#the_async_iterator_and_async_iterable_protocols]:

for await (const chunk of source) {
// chunk: Uint8Array — one TCP segment
// await is permitted here
yield transform(chunk); // send transformed bytes downstream
// return to stop after first chunk (common for prefix-stripping)
}

Yield value │ Meaning

Uint8Array │ Raw bytes copied verbatim.

string │ Bytes interpreted as UTF-8 / ASCII characters.

No yield before return │ No bytes emitted (HTTP parser receives empty input — likely a 400 response).

throw / exception │ Connection closed; error logged.

6.1.4. Filter chaining

Multiple addL4Filter calls chain in registration order. The accumulated output of filter N is delivered as a single chunk to filter N+1’s source.

// Filter 1: strip a 4-byte binary frame header
srv.addL4Filter(async function*(source) {
for await (const chunk of source) {
yield chunk.slice(4);
return;
}
});
// Filter 2: log the stripped payload
srv.addL4Filter(async function*(source) {
for await (const chunk of source) {
nginx.log(nginx.DEBUG,
'inbound ' + chunk.length + ' bytes after strip');
yield chunk;
return;
}
});

Outbound:addL4SendFilter(fn)

Intercepts bytes travelling from nginx to the client, after the HTTP response is fully formed.

6.2.1. On JS-managed listeners

listener.addL4SendFilter(async function*(source) {
for await (const chunk of source) {
yield appendSignature(chunk);
}
});

6.2.2. On standard listen sockets

srv.addL4SendFilter(async function*(source) {
for await (const chunk of source) {
yield chunk; // pass through; can transform instead
}
});

The generator protocol is identical to addL4Filter. The filter hooks into c→send / c→send_chain via pool-cleanup type-tagged state. EOF is delivered lazily inside the collect loop after the first yield.

Availability Matrix

Target │ addL4Filter │ addL4SendFilter

JS-managed listener (nginx.http.attach(sock)) │ Yes │ Yes

Standard listen socket (via server.addL4Filter) │ Yes │ Yes

Async vs. Sync Inside the Generator

await is fully supported inside L4 generator bodies. When the generator suspends at an await, the connection is parked in w→l4_pending and the event loop continues processing other requests. When the awaited Promise settles, ngx_js_l4_async_check resumes the generator.

// Example: async lookup before forwarding
srv.addL4Filter(async function*(source) {
for await (const chunk of source) {
await nginx.setTimeout(5); // simulate async work
yield chunk;
return;
}
});

Cross-Worker Shared State

7.1.nginx.shared

nginx.shared is a flat key/value store backed by a dedicated shared-memory zone. All nginx worker processes read and write the same memory region — a value written in one worker is immediately visible to every other worker.

// Write from any request handler
nginx.shared.set('rate:192.168.1.1', '42');
// Read from any worker
var hits = nginx.shared.get('rate:192.168.1.1'); // → '42' or undefined
// Atomic counter
nginx.shared.incr('total_requests'); // → 1, 2, 3, …
nginx.shared.incr('total_requests', 5); // add 5
// Cleanup
nginx.shared.delete('rate:192.168.1.1'); // → true | false
var keys = nginx.shared.keys(); // → string[]

Method Reference

Method │ Returns │ Behaviour

get(key) │ string | undefined │ Returns the stored value, or undefined if the key does not exist.

set(key, val) │ undefined │ Stores val for key. Creates or overwrites. Throws RangeError if key > 127 chars or value > 511 chars. Throws InternalError if the store is full (256 entries).

delete(key) │ boolean │ Removes key. Returns true if the key existed.

keys() │ string[] │ Returns an unsorted array of all live keys.

incr(key[, delta=1]) │ number │ Parses the current value as a base-10 integer, adds delta (default 1), stores and returns the result. Non-numeric values are treated as 0; missing keys start at 0. The entire operation is atomic.

Limits

Limit │ Value

Maximum key length │ 127 characters

Maximum value length │ 511 characters

Maximum entries │ 256

Total zone size │ ≈ 163 kB

Whennginx.sharedIs Available

The shared-memory zone is mapped after config parsing. nginx.shared methods are safe to call from request-phase handlers, hooks, and timer callbacks. Calling them from top-level js_source code (i.e., during init_conf) throws InternalError.

Concurrency

All five methods acquire a spinlock for the duration of the operation. incr is atomic — no application-level locking is required.

Persistence Across Hot-Reload

nginx.shared data survives nginx -s reload. The init callback detects the hot-reload case (data != NULL) and preserves existing entries.

Master Lifecycle Events

8.1.nginx.on(event, fn)

Registers a callback to be invoked in the master process when nginx lifecycle events occur.

nginx.on('workerSpawned', function(pid, slot) {
nginx.log(nginx.INFO, 'worker ' + pid + ' started (slot ' + slot + ')');
});
nginx.on('workerExited', function(pid, slot, status) {
nginx.log(nginx.WARN, 'worker ' + pid + ' exited with status ' + status);
});
nginx.on('quit', function() { /* SIGQUIT received */ });
nginx.on('reload', function() { /* SIGHUP received */ });
nginx.on('reloaded', function() { /* new config active */ });
nginx.on('reopen', function() { /* SIGUSR1 received */ });

Multiple calls register multiple listeners for the same event; all run in registration order.

Event Reference

Event │ Callback signature │ When it fires

workerSpawned │ function(pid, slot) │ A new worker process has been forked. pid — OS process ID. slot — index in ngx_processes[].

workerExited │ function(pid, slot, status) │ A worker process has exited. status — the raw waitpid status value (use WEXITSTATUS(status) etc. in C; in JS this is the raw integer).

quit │ function() │ SIGQUIT received. The master is beginning graceful shutdown.

reload │ function() │ SIGHUP received. nginx is about to re-read the configuration file.

reloaded │ function() │ Hot-reload is complete and the new worker generation is active.

reopen │ function() │ SIGUSR1 received. Log files are being reopened (log rotation).

Constraints

•

Callbacks run in the master process JS context, not in a worker.

•

Callbacks must be synchronous. Returning a Promise is ignored.

•

nginx.on() must be called from js_source (init time), not from a request handler.

Module System

Loading Filesystem Plugins:nginx.use(path[, config])

Loads a plugin package from the local filesystem.

nginx.use('/opt/plugins/auth-guard', { secret: process.env.AUTH_SECRET });
nginx.use('/opt/plugins/rate-limiter', { rps: 500 });

Returns nginx for chaining.

9.1.1. Entry-point resolution

1.

Read <path>/package.json if it exists.

2.

If package.json has a ngxjs.main key, use <path>/<ngxjs.main>.

3.

Otherwise fall back to <path>/index.js.

9.1.2. package.json format

Only the ngxjs key is read; all other fields are ignored:

{
"name": "my-plugin",
"version": "1.0.0",
"ngxjs": {
"main": "src/plugin.js"
}
}

9.1.3. Inside the plugin script

The entry file is evaluated as an ES module. nginx.pluginConfig holds the config argument:

// opt/plugins/auth-guard/index.js
var cfg = nginx.pluginConfig;
nginx.http.addHook(function(req) {
if (req.headers['x-token'] !== cfg.secret) {
req.respond(401, {}, 'Unauthorized\n');
}
});

Installing Inline Plugins:nginx.install(plugin[, config])

Installs a plugin without touching the filesystem.

// Object with .install method
nginx.install({
install: function(cfg) {
nginx.http.addHook(function(req) {
req.respond(200, {}, cfg.greeting + '\n');
});
}
}, { greeting: 'Hello!' });
// Bare function
nginx.install(function(cfg) {
nginx.log(nginx.INFO, 'plugin config: ' + JSON.stringify(cfg));
}, { debug: true });

Returns the return value of the plugin call.

Hot Reload:nginx.use()from a Request Handler

nginx.use() can also be called from a worker request handler (not only at init time). When called from a worker, the plugin is loaded locally, then a NGX_CMD_JS_USE_PLUGIN message is sent to the master, which broadcasts a NGX_CMD_JS_LOAD_PLUGIN command to all other workers. All workers end up with the same plugin loaded without nginx restart or reload.

loc.handler = async function(req) {
var path = req.headers['x-plugin-path'];
if (path) {
nginx.use(path); // loads locally + broadcasts to all workers
req.respond(200, {}, 'plugin loaded\n');
return;
}
req.respond(404, {}, 'not found\n');
};

: Hot-loaded plugins are not persisted across nginx restart. Add the nginx.use() call to the js_source script to make a plugin permanent.

Complete Examples

Authentication Middleware

Global auth check with per-request context passing:

// Global HTTP hook: validate JWT and store claims in req.ctx
nginx.http.addHook(async function(req) {
var authHeader = req.headers['authorization'] || '';
if (!authHeader.startsWith('Bearer ')) {
req.respond(401, {'WWW-Authenticate': 'Bearer realm="api"'}, '');
return;
}
var token = parseJWT(authHeader.slice(7));
if (!token) {
req.respond(403, {}, 'Invalid token\n');
return;
}
req.ctx.userId = token.sub;
req.ctx.roles = token.roles;
});
// Content handler: use claims from req.ctx
nginx.http.servers[0].locations[0].handler = function(req) {
if (!req.ctx.roles.includes('admin')) {
req.respond(403, {}, 'Forbidden\n');
return;
}
req.respond(200, {}, 'Hello admin ' + req.ctx.userId + '\n');
};

Rate Limiting at the TCP Level

Accept hook with a per-IP token bucket stored in nginx.shared:

var srv = nginx.http.servers[0];
srv.on('accept', function(conn) {
var key = 'rate:' + conn.remoteAddr;
var now = Math.floor(Date.now() / 1000);
var ts = parseInt(nginx.shared.get(key + ':ts') || '0');
// Refill tokens (max 10, 1 per second)
var tokens = parseInt(nginx.shared.get(key + ':t') || '10');
if (now > ts) {
tokens = Math.min(10, tokens + (now - ts));
nginx.shared.set(key + ':ts', String(now));
}
if (tokens <= 0) {
nginx.log(nginx.WARN, 'rate-limit: ' + conn.remoteAddr);
conn.reject();
return;
}
nginx.shared.set(key + ':t', String(tokens - 1));
});

Middleware Timing Wrapper

Wrap the entire hook chain for a location with request timing:

var loc = nginx.http.servers[0].locations.find(
function(l) { return l.path === '/api/'; }
);
// Outer: measures total hook + handler time
loc.addHook(async function(req, next) {
var t0 = Date.now();
await next();
nginx.log(nginx.INFO,
req.method + ' ' + req.uri + ' ' + (Date.now() - t0) + 'ms');
});
// Inner: the actual auth check
loc.addHook(function(req) {
if (!req.headers['x-api-key']) {
req.respond(401, {}, 'Missing key\n');
}
});

L4 Protocol Negotiation

Strip a custom binary handshake before HTTP parsing:

const MAGIC = 'NGXJS:';
nginx.http.servers[0].addL4Filter(async function*(source) {
for await (const chunk of source) {
var s = String.fromCharCode(...chunk);
if (s.startsWith(MAGIC)) {
nginx.log(nginx.INFO, 'ngxjs handshake from client');
yield s.slice(MAGIC.length);
} else {
yield s; // plain HTTP — forward unchanged
}
return; // one chunk is enough
}
});

Cross-Worker Hit Counter Plugin

A plugin loaded with nginx.use() that counts requests across all workers:

// /opt/plugins/hit-counter/index.js
var cfg = nginx.pluginConfig;
var location = cfg.location; // e.g. '/stats'
nginx.http.addHook(function(req) {
nginx.shared.incr('hits');
});
var statsLoc = nginx.http.servers[0].locations.find(
function(l) { return l.path === location; }
);
if (statsLoc) {
statsLoc.handler = function(req) {
var n = nginx.shared.get('hits') || '0';
req.respond(200, {'Content-Type': 'text/plain'}, 'hits: ' + n + '\n');
};
}

// js_source:
nginx.use('/opt/plugins/hit-counter', { location: '/stats' });

Reference

Hook API Summary

Method │ Scope │ When it fires

nginx.http.addHook(fn) │ Global HTTP │ Access phase — every request in the HTTP block

server.addHook(fn) │ Virtual server │ Access phase — every request on this server

location.addHook(fn) │ Location │ Content phase — every request matched to this location

location.addResponseHook(fn) │ Location │ After content handler selects headers, before they are sent

Accept Hook API Summary

Method │ Target │ Notes

listener.on('accept', fn) │ JS-managed listener │ JS-managed listeners created via nginx.http.attach(sock).

server.on('accept', fn) │ Standard listen socket │ Sockets declared with nginx’s listen directive.

L4 Filter API Summary

Method │ Direction │ Notes

listener.addL4Filter(fn) / server.addL4Filter(fn) │ Client → nginx (inbound) │ Before HTTP parsing. Async generator, await supported.

listener.addL4SendFilter(fn) / server.addL4SendFilter(fn) │ Nginx → client (outbound) │ After HTTP response is formed. Async generator, await supported.

Upstream Filter API Summary

Method │ Direction

location.addUpstreamFilter(fn) │ Upstream response body (server → client)

location.addUpstreamRequestFilter(fn) │ Client request body (client → upstream)

11.5.nginx.onEvent Reference

Event │ Signature │ Trigger

workerSpawned │ fn(pid, slot) │ Worker forked

workerExited │ fn(pid, slot, status) │ Worker exited

quit │ fn() │ SIGQUIT — graceful shutdown begins

reload │ fn() │ SIGHUP — config re-read begins

reloaded │ fn() │ New worker generation active

reopen │ fn() │ SIGUSR1 — log rotation

11.6.nginx.sharedLimits

Limit │ Value

Max key length │ 127 characters

Max value length │ 511 characters

Max entries │ 256

Zone size │ ≈ 163 kB

Error Handling Summary

Situation │ Behaviour

Hook throws synchronously │ nginx logs the error; 500 response sent.

Async hook’s Promise rejects │ nginx logs the error; 500 response sent.

Accept hook returns a Promise │ Connection rejected; warning logged.

L4 filter generator throws │ Connection closed; error logged.

nginx.shared.set when full │ InternalError thrown to the caller.

nginx.shared.set with oversized key/value │ RangeError thrown to the caller.

nginx.on callback throws │ Error logged; remaining listeners for the same event still run.